<!DOCTYPE html><html lang="en" ><head><meta charset="UTF-8"><meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0"><meta name="generator" content="Jekyll v4.1.0" /><meta property="og:title" content="JavaScript Developer" /><meta name="author" content="snuthern" /><meta property="og:locale" content="en_US" /><meta name="description" content="Just a simple developer portfolio and blog dedicated to @Snuthern" /><meta property="og:description" content="Just a simple developer portfolio and blog dedicated to @Snuthern" /><link rel="canonical" href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" /><meta property="og:url" content="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" /><meta property="og:site_name" content="JavaScript Developer" /><meta name="twitter:card" content="summary" /><meta property="twitter:title" content="JavaScript Developer" /><meta name="twitter:site" content="@snuthern" /><meta name="twitter:creator" content="@snuthern" /> <script type="application/ld+json"> {"@type":"WebPage","url":"http://localhost:4000/atom.xml","headline":"JavaScript Developer","author":{"@type":"Person","name":"snuthern"},"description":"Just a simple developer portfolio and blog dedicated to @Snuthern","@context":"https://schema.org"}</script><title> JavaScript Developer - Just a simple developer portfolio and blog dedicated to @Snuthern</title><link rel="shortcut icon" href="/favicon.png"><link rel="alternate" type="application/atom+xml" title="JavaScript Developer" href="/atom.xml"><link rel="alternate" type="application/json" title="JavaScript Developer" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.json" /><link rel="sitemap" type="application/xml" title="sitemap" href="/sitemap.xml" /><style> *,:after,:before{box-sizing:border-box;background-color:inherit;color:inherit;margin:0;padding:0}body{font-family:system-ui, sans-serif;-webkit-font-smoothing:antialiased;text-rendering:optimizeLegibility;line-height:1.5;font-size:1rem;color:#16171a}nav ul{border-right:1px solid #edf2f7}a{color:#000;text-decoration-skip-ink:auto;text-decoration:underline}pre{margin:.5rem 0;padding:.5rem}.post p{margin:.5rem 0}.post h1,.post h2,.post h3,.post h4{margin:1rem 0}.post h2:first-child,.project h2:first-child,.photo h2:first-child{margin-top:0}.meta{margin:2rem 0}code,pre{background:#ecedee}code{padding:.1rem}pre code{border:none}pre{padding:1rem;overflow-x:auto}img{max-width:100%}hr{background:#000;height:1px;border:0}header{flex-basis:10rem;flex-grow:1;position:relative}header a{text-decoration:none}header li{margin-bottom:.2rem;text-align:right;margin-right:2rem}header a.active{font-weight:bold}header,section{padding:1rem}blockquote{font-style:italic;border-left:5px solid #ececec;padding-left:1rem}h1,h2,h3,h4,h5{line-height:1;margin:1rem 0;font-weight:600}section h1:first-child{margin-top:0}strong,b{font-weight:bold}.photos ul{list-style:none}.photos li{margin-bottom:1.5rem}.photo picture,.project picture{margin-bottom:0.5rem}.posts ul,header ul{list-style:none}.posts li{align-items:center;display:flex;justify-content:space-between;margin-bottom:.5rem}.posts li a,.posts li div,.projects li a{white-space:nowrap;overflow:hidden;text-overflow:ellipsis;text-decoration:none}.posts li time,.projects li time{padding-left:1rem;white-space:nowrap;font-variant-numeric:tabular-nums}main{display:flex;flex-wrap:wrap;max-width:60rem;margin:2rem auto;padding:1rem}@media screen and (max-width: 45rem){header li{display:inline;margin-right:1rem}.logo{padding-bottom:1rem}header ul{border-bottom:1px solid #edf2f7;padding-bottom:2rem}nav ul{border-right:0px}.photos ul{margin-top:0.5rem}}section{flex-basis:0;flex-grow:999;min-width:70%;display:flex;flex-direction:column}figcaption{font-size:smaller}</style></head><body><main role="main"><header role="banner"> <!--<h1 class="logo">JavaScript Developer</h1>--><nav role="navigation"><ul><li><a href="/" >Home</a></li><li><a href="/blog" >Articles</a></li><li><a href="/projects" >Projects</a></li><li><a href="/resume" >Resume</a></li><li><a href="/contact" >Contact</a></li><li><a href="/about" >About</a></li></ul></nav></header><section class="post"><h2></h2><?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> <feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>JavaScript Developer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/><link href="http://localhost:4000/"/> <updated>2020-06-11T14:11:03-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000</id> <author> <name>snuthern</name> <email>yossi@jsdevs.pro</email> </author> <entry><title>Oh Em Gee!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/11/oh-em-gee"/> <updated>2020-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/11/oh-em-gee</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have been using Github for years and never have I ever done some mess like this!! I am creating a Deno module for Discord called &lt;strong&gt;DiscordTS&lt;/strong&gt; keep an eye out for it. I created the repo on github and cloned it locally. I then went about my normal process of workflow and for three days I worked on this project and added numerous files and folders. I then went about the normal process of pushing my changes to github with one minor change. I was using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit -am &quot;Message&lt;/code&gt; shorthand to add files to the staging area, but wasn’t looking at exactly what it was staging.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I pushed all of my changes and was doing some reordering on my repo directory. I had a few to rename and move and a couple to delete. I deleted the local copy since the repo is always there on GIthub…. So later I login to GH and go to my repo and guess what? Nothing there… Somehow the shorthand &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit -am &quot;Message&quot;&lt;/code&gt; doesn’t do the same thing as adding all files via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add *&lt;/code&gt; so all that was there was 2 files I had changed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So here I sit, coding the entire freaking thing again :D&lt;br /&gt; Lesson learned, Until next time….&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry><title>First Impressions On Deno</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/07/first-impressions-on-deno"/> <updated>2020-06-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/07/first-impressions-on-deno</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days I have been setting up deno and playing around with it. I have to say I am REALLY enjoying it so far. Working with TypeScript in Node can be a pain at times, running the compiler, then node just to serve up a page. Deno reduces all of that down to a simple &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;deno run file.ts&lt;/code&gt; which I know isn’t much, but in terms of production environments that was time saved, which equals $$&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Beyond that, I enjoy how coming over to Deno isn’t as difficult as you would imagine for a Node developer. Most of the Node packages are already there and you can even import them using a simple &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;import { whatever_from_node } from &quot;https://deno.land/std/node/module.ts&quot;&lt;/code&gt; it doesn’t have &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; that npm does, but it has many of the common ones.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the most part all you need to do to get started with Deno is just change your extensions to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.ts&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.js&lt;/code&gt; and start adding what &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; of parameters you are expecting, it will start to give you errors but they aren’t difficult to trace down. For a simple tutorial on how to migrate from JavaScript to TypeScript there is one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/handbook/migrating-from-javascript.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typescriptlang.org/docs/home.html&quot;&gt;TypeScript Docs&lt;/a&gt; is another great source of help.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is even an edX course from MicroSoft on an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edx.org/course/introduction-to-typescript-2&quot;&gt;“Intro to TypeScript”&lt;/a&gt; where you can get an introduction to the language. If you are already familiar with OOP and typed languages in general moving over isn’t too big of an issue. I hope you all enjoy digging in…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/practicaldev/image/fetch/s--rRQOkKpj--/c_imagga_scale,f_auto,fl_progressive,h_420,q_auto,w_1000/https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/g5lkpi1owrkthyjw3k7r.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image.Deno_Land&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry><title>A Free Cloud IDE With Perks!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/28/free-cloud-ide"/> <updated>2020-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/28/free-cloud-ide</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love to find free resources online for developers and this one is amazing! Many times I am asked for a free resource to somewhere to develop node apps or typescript apps. I found this little gem a while back and have been testing it. They set you up on the free account with 5 “containers”, a CLoud IDE connected to your container and 10 Gigs to play around with.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You also have access to a Linux server of your choosing when you set up. They support numerous languages out of the box and I have really enjoyed it so far. I set up a CodeAnywhere account and it was a little tough to understand where everything is, how to install, etc. None of those problems greeted me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://goorm.io&quot;&gt;Goorm.io&lt;/a&gt; I was up and running in no time, and with only a couple of dollars a month I can upgrade to a persistant box with way more features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Combine Goorm + DigitalOcean and build your own development web server for a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry><title>Working with Express.Js</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/working-with-express"/> <updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/22/working-with-express</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the Coronavirus pandemic hit America there have been many APIs built to pull the data for new infections, hospitalizations, deaths, and more. I wanted to start learning Express.js so I set out to build a simple dashboard where I could view data for my State and I figured create it so others from other States could do the same.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At first “routing” made no sense to me, why do I need to create 3 seperate files just to have a simple HTML page render, but I got over that. After I somewhat got the basics of rendering down I started building. I enjoy the ease of being able to create URL parameters the way Express does, Im going to jump into Angular, Vue, React and more once I get this one built to what I envision.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you would like to take a look at my project and send me some constructive criticism I would be more than happy to hear from you. You can find the link to my Discord ID on my profile. Until then I am going back to working on this and will post some more in a few days.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry><title>Learning.Js Is TOUGH!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/14/learning-js"/> <updated>2020-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/14/learning-js</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I enjoy working with JavaScript, it is one of my main languages that I develop in. I get questions from many newbies to the code world about how difficult it is. It has progressed so much though compared to the late 90s when it was first developing online. You couldn’t really do anything cool with it you just were able to add some features to websites that made for a &lt;em&gt;“better UI/UX”&lt;/em&gt; for the user. Most people who visited websites disagreed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mainly you would see people using it for buttons and flashing images or something ridiculous like that. We couldn’t yet really manipulate the DOM like we can now, and jQuery was not yet invented. You couldn’t use it for data and the crazy amount of things you can today. It was unheard of for someone to be able to create a http server and host a website just using JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now with the emergence of TypeScript we have the added functionality of being able to add types to JavaScript. This is more an aspect of enterprise development and it isn’t something most web developers are even used to messing with. Some of the languages you learn after JavaScript have more use in corporate work. Some are better used for game development, some are better used for databases and ORM.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is a whole world out there after you learn JavaScript&lt;br /&gt; Never stop learning!&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> <entry><title>Day One Of A New Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/13/day-one-blog"/> <updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated> <id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/13/day-one-blog</id> <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well. Finally got around to putting this old website together. Neat thing about it - powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; and I can use Markdown to author my posts. It actually is a lot easier than I thought it was going to be. I just wanted to get a post up so I can call it a blog. Sometimes it is tough for me to be consistant with a blog so I will try to be more about this one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I use a variety of JavaScript libraries and frameworks on the daily as a freelance developer, I also run a Discord server dedicated to pairing new programmers with older mentors who can help them learn to write cleaner more efficient code. We mainly use Discords API and YouTube API and our own internal API to teach emerging coders how to communicate with the servers and improve their own skills.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Feel free to stop by our server and get to know the crew, we have members from all over the world who sign on all different times so you are bound to meet someone. We have giveaways and prizes for our regular members and more. Discord URL is &lt;a href=&quot;https://dicord.gg/mhMrZzk&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, we teach everything from UI/UX design and wireframing an app / website, all the way up to how to code your own server and site in Node.Js and manage your own modules within that site.&lt;/p&gt; </content> </entry> </feed></section></main></body></html>
